

■ joey.mckenzie27@gmail.com | 🌴 joeymckenzie.tech | 🖸 JoeyMcKenzie | 🛅 JoeyMcKenzie | 💆 joeyMcKenzie | 🍎 the_beercoder

Summary.

Seasoned professional software developer with diverse experience building enterprise-grade distributed software systems with technologies in .NET, Java, and TypeScript across industries including healthcare, insurance, manufacturing, and fintech. I specialize in building fast, efficient cloud-based web services and APIs with AWS and Azure alongside modern web applications with Angular, React, and Vue. I have a passion for software architecture and design, software leadership and mentorship, and delivering high-quality software products at a nationwide scale.

I am an avid contributor to open source, primarily in the Rust and TypeScript ecosystems, alongside minor contributions in Go with community projects hosted across GitHub, Vercel and Netlify. I enjoy dispersing knowledge and experience with other like-minded developers sharing a similar passion for software development and design. I write and produce technical content on my blog, Twitch, and YouTube exploring emerging technologies with a focus on developer advocacy.

Experience

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

National Funding

- · Developing .NET microservices, React applications with Next.js, and AWS infrastructure supporting financial operations
- Migrating legacy services to serverless architectures with AWS Lambda, API Gateway, EventBridge, S3, and SQS
- Integrating external financial partner APIs into backend systems, increasing customer lending conversion by up to 40%
- Managing CI/CD pipelines and automated processes with AWS, Terraform, Jenkins, and containerized workflows with Docker
- Upgrading internal .NET infrastructure improving performance and speed by 25% while reducing AWS costs
- Troubleshooting applications errors using log aggregation services with OpenSearch and Kibana
- Maintaining company-wide build artifacts with **NuGet** and source code with **GitHub**
- · Participating in agile scrum ceremonies and using productivity tools in Confluence, Slack, and Jira

MediKeeper Remote

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Dec 2020 - Jan 2022

- Developed .NET and JavaScript applications with Vue deployed to Azure infrastructure
- · Worked with product teams and UX designers to compose Sass and Material Design-based UIs with Figma
- Migrated existing CI/CD pipelines and automated processes to Azure DevOps to improve existing build times
- Administered SQL Server and Oracle databases while improving business critical query times by up to 35%
- · Improved existing system architecture by migrating legacy .NET Framework applications to modern .NET
- · Maintained integration suites with JavaScript and Cypress to automate platform testing, increasing QA velocity by 20%
- · Participated in agile scrum ceremonies and using productivity tools in Confluence, Slack, and Jira

Sierra Pacific Industries Redding, CA

Jan. 2020 - Dec. 2020 SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Developed internal applications and dashboards using modern RPG ILE on the IBM iSeries AS/400 and .NET for desktop applications
- Migrated brownfield and legacy applications to modern RPG architectures increasing application response times
- Improved business critical PL/SQL queries for embedded systems by up to 40% in several applications
- Maintained company-wide build artifacts with RDi, Azure DevOps, and VSTS
- · Managed database schemas with SQL Server using SSMS to support inventory management operations

VSP Global Sacramento, CA

• Developed Java APIs and Angular applications with TypeScript deployed to AWS hosting infrastructure

- Migrated legacy JEE and Spring applications to Spring Boot while increasing response times by up to 25%
- · Lead development of Angular applications utilizing Material Design, Sass, RxJS, NgRx, and modern web standards
- · Created and maintained CI/CD pipelines with Jenkins, Chef, and containterized workflows with Docker
- Administrated systems and servers while migrating non-production workloads off legacy Windows servers to Linux servers
- Maintained company-wide build artifacts with Artifcatory and source code with BitBucket
- Assisted in troubleshooting company-wide service outages and application performance issues with Splunk and Wily
- · Participated in agile scrum ceremonies and using productivity tools in Confluence, Slack, and Jira

Engility Corporation San Diego, CA

Wrote and maintained VBA and R codebases to perform data analysis and spreadsheet specific functionality

- Provided contractor support for U.S. Department of Defense naval programs for systems engineering and data analysis
- · Performed regression analysis and statistical programming using R to refine estimated financial expenditure models
- · Managed automated Excel spreadsheets and codebases in RStudio for data analysis and exploration
- Maintained databases of financial data and provided ad hoc SQL reporting for various projects

Education

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

OPERATIONS RESEARCH ANALYST

San Diego State University B.S. IN ASTROPHYSICS, MINOR IN MATHEMATICS

Jun. 2018 - Jan. 2020

Sept. 2016 - May 2018

Jan. 2022 - Present